# Vincent Vo

Systems Administrator | Identity & Access Management | Automation & Security linkedin.com/in/vovincent12 | vincenttyo.github.io

## **Professional Summary**

Efficiency-driven IT Systems Administrator specializing in **Identity & Access Management and** automation, enhancing user lifecycle management through Okta, Google Workspace, Workato, and APIs. Expertise in enforcing **Zero Trust Policies**, Role-Based Access Controls (RBAC), and Privileged Access Management (PAM) to enhance security posture. Proven success in **implementing foundational ITSM programs**, endpoint security (Kandji MDM, SentinelOne EDR), and SaaS integrations–enhancing corporate security, business, and user efficiency.

## Core Competencies & Key Skills

- Identity & Access Management (IAM) & PAM: RBAC, Zero Trust, Adaptive MFA, SSO (SAML/OAuth)
- Automation & Scripting: Workato, BetterCloud, Python, Bash, REST APIs
- Cloud & Endpoint Security: Okta, Google Workspace, Microsoft 365, Kandji (MDM), SentinelOne (EDR)
- Lifecycle & ITSM: Provisioning, Onboarding/Offboarding, ServiceNow, Jira, Confluence
- Security Operations: Access Reviews, Adaptive MFA, Network Segmentation, SSO Implementation
- Integration & Secrets Management: API Integrations, 1Password

# **Experience**

## IT Systems Administrator | Measurabl, San Diego, CA

May 2022 - Present

- Automated IAM workflows, reducing provisional errors by 67% through integrating SaaS
  applications into Okta using SAML, OIDC, OAuth and SCIM, enabling SSO, automated provisioning and
  centralized authentication.
- Drove enforcement of RBAC, Device Trust, PAM policies reducing access requests by 50%, enhancing Zero Trust security, least privileged access, and conditional access for 200+ users.
- Optimized core systems (Okta, Google Workspace, Kandji, Slack) increasing administrative
  efficiency by 25% through feature adoption and integrating systems using Workato (IPaaS), REST APIs,
  and scripts.
- Deployed CIS benchmark policies via Kandj increasing Mac security compliance by 75%, reducing IT overhead and improving user uptime.
- Obtained SOC2 Type 2 certification by monitoring Drata, collecting provisioned access evidence, auditing user permissions and alerts in Okta, Google Workspace, SentinelOne, and reviewing security policies.

#### **Senior Service Desk Analyst** | Realty Income, San Diego, CA

July 2020 - May 2022

Promoted to Senior Service Desk Analyst in December 2021 initially hired as a Service Desk Analyst. Taking on advanced responsibilities. Leading the Service Desk Team and development of ITIL and Security practices.

- Reduced unauthorized access by 15% by enforcing least privileged access using Active Directory, Okta, and group policies, automating user provisioning, improving security and compliance.
- Increased system uptime and user productivity by administering Microsoft 365, Active Directory,
   Okta, and group policies, optimizing SaaS integrations and access management.
- Led a team of 5 improving ticket resolution by 25%, improving IT service delivery for end users.

- Improved SOX audit compliance by capturing evidence and audit logging, reducing audit friction and ensuring adherence to SOX controls.
- Managed PDQ Deploy for patch management for 200+ endpoints, automating security updates and maintaining system compliance.

#### Client Services Engineer | CARET (fka AbacusNext), San Diego, CA December 2018 - July 2020

- **Enhanced user experience for 300+ clients** by managing VMware Horizon virtual machines using Active Directory, group policies, patch management, and solving technical issues related to their used applications.
- Improved the efficiency of virtual machines for business client users by automating computer maintenance tasks with BAT scripts for disk drive cleaning, application management, and patch file removal.
- **Ensured satisfactory client issue resolution and optimized windows server performance** by collaborating with cloud engineers, providing exceptional service delivery.

#### Certifications

- **BetterCloud Administrator** | BetterCloud 2023
- ITIL 4 Strategist: Direct, Plan, and Improve | PeopleCert 2021
- ITIL 4 Foundation | PeopleCert 2021
- Google IT Support Professional | Coursera 2019

#### **Education**

Bachelor's in Interdisciplinary Studies (Kinesiology, Psychology, Sociology) | San Diego State University